Miles Loveday

contactme@milesloveday.com

Personal Statement

I am a full stack web developer (tending towards front end development and improving legacy code) with experience of greenfield and legacy projects in Java, PHP and JS/TS (React, Knockout), having worked for clients including the BBC and David Lloyd Leisure. Prior to becoming a developer I had a background in teaching secondary mathematics at top UK schools and studied Information Engineering at the University of Cambridge. I am currently a full time stay at home parent, with a specialty in long distance running.

Employment History

03/2017 - present

Self employed

PT Dev / Stay at home dad

Part time developing a custom web project in PHP/Symfony, Typescript/React for a local pub to plan/manage staff rota, store accounting data, track revenue, receipts, labour rates, etc (<u>demo</u>, <u>write up</u>). Also looking after my children.

02/2018 Softwire Part time contractor

Contractor to help with a support backlog at my previous employer

08/2014 - 06/2017 Softwire Software Developer

Developer working on various client projects including BBC Music and David Lloyd Leisure

01/2013 - 08/2012 Walthamstow Hall, Sevenoaks Teacher of mathematics

Teaching 11-18 year old students. Included IGCSE, A-level and Pre-U

09/2008 - 12/2012 King Edward's School, Teacher of mathematics

Birmingham

Teaching 11-18 year old students. Included IGCSE, A-level and IB.

09/2005 - 04/2007 Metsec Plc Project Engineer

Designing and developing software to track issues in manufacturing, in Pascal/SQL Server

Skills learned

React, Knockout

Using Typescript, Webpack, Grunt, Gulp, Encore for SPAs. Implementing React projects from scratch on a greenfield project (and various personal projects), updating a sizeable Knockout project to use Typescript to aid development

Cross-platform mobile with Phonegap

Developing for iOS and Android

Microservices

Developing with microservices, improving development where tickets change multiple services

Developing with and improving legacy code

Working with a large, monolithic codebase. Improving code readability through refactoring, adding and improving documentation and replacing poorly performing code. Debugging obscure bugs and applying fixes.

Performance testing and monitoring with Gatling and NewRelic

Implementing a Jenkins job and Gatling tests to get metrics for performance improvements before and after code changes; monitoring NewRelic and responding to issues; proactively looking for the next bottleneck and the next, least difficult, potential performance gains

MySQL query optimisation

Improving performance with targeted indexes and guery tweaks

PHP development with Zend 1 and Symfony 3 & 4

Includes setting up new Symfony projects

Working as part of a team

Developing standards to work to (linting, code review) and improving development process (e.g. documentation, speeding up tests run locally)

Testing

Improving unit test coverage, implementing integration tests. Worked with Phockito, Cucumber, Enzyme, Jest, Mocha amongst others

Education

2007 - 2008

Birmingham University

PGCE in Secondary Mathematics

Secondary Mathematics teaching qualification

2001 - 2005

University of Cambridge

Information Engineering

B.A., Engineering (Information Engineering), 2:2

Projects: 'Production Scheduling' & 'Image Processing'

Modules: Signals and Systems, Systems and Control, Signal and Pattern Processing, Data Transmission,

Computer and Network Systems, Software Engineering and Design, Introduction to Bioscience,

Physiological Systems, Business Economics, Organisational Behaviour and Change.

1994 - 2001

King Edward VI Camp Hill,

GCSE, A-levels

Birmingham

AAA in Maths, Further Maths, Physics at A-level 3 Grade A*, 5 Grade A, 2 Grade B at GCSE

Interests

Running

Active runner, having taken it up in 2017. Member of Kings Heath Running club. Completed many half marathons, most recently completed a trail marathon (Endurancelife CTS Northumberland).

Photography

Avid photographer, particularly of people, happiest lugging around far more equipment than necessary for a good shot.